（流子(りゅうこ)の荒い息遣い）
Ryuuko!
（マコ）流子ちゃん！
（鮮血(せんけつ)）大丈夫なのか？
Are you okay?!
This hurts like hell!
It freakin' kills!
（流子）痛(いて)ーよ！ すげえ痛え
But it's just what I deserve for
acting like such a complete and utter fool!
でも大バカな私には当然の報いだ
I can't believe you're still alive
after severing your Life Fibers.
（縫(ぬい)）信じられない
生命戦維(せんい)を切断して生きてるなんて
...However...
だけど…
Nui's wounds healed!
（蛇崩(じゃくずれ)）縫の傷が治ってく
So she's immortal too?
（猿投山(さなげやま)）
ヤツも不死身ということか
That's the power of the
Life Fibers within her body.
（黄長瀬(きながせ)）体内の生命戦維の力だ
Throwing your Sword Scissor
at me was a mistake.
ハサミを投げたのはうかつだったね
僕を倒すことはできないし—
It wasn't enough to kill me,
and now they're both in my hands.
これで２本とも僕のものになった
Go, Senketsu!
（マコ）行って 鮮血ちゃん！
流子ちゃんの元へ！
To Ryuuko!
Sure!
（鮮血）おう！
（縫）フン 鮮血ごとき
またズタズタだよ
Too bad, Senketsu.
You're getting ripped to shreds again!
Not if I can help it!
（鮮血）やらせるか！
Hey, I'm not your springboard!
僕を踏み台にした
Let's go, Ryuuko!
（鮮血）行くぞ 流子！
Life Fiber Synchronize!
人衣(じんい)一体！
（縫）ヒャッ！
（美木杉(みきすぎ)たち）フッ
（マコ）うわ〜
（皐月(さつき)）フッ
EPISODE 22
TELL ME
HOW YOU FEEL
unmei no ito wo tachikitta sono saki ni
It all begins when we sever the threads of fate
senobi shiteitanda
I was trying to be someone I'm not
kutsuzure darake no
In a cramped world
semai sekai de
With no breathing room
runway wo aruku
As I walked down my runway
egao no uragawa
I thought I'd concealed it
kakushita tsumori de
Behind the smile that masked my face
dakedo itsumo kimi ni wa
But it doesn't work on you
minukarete shimatte ite
You always see through my facade
konna no wa hajimete de
Nobody's ever unraveled me like this before
tomadou kedo
I don't know what to do
hoka no dare ni mo kikonasenai
Nobody else can pull these outfits off
nandaka wakannai
A somewhat ambiguous fever
atsusa ga mune wo kogasu kara
Threatens to burn our hearts away
unmei no ito taguriyoseta sono saki ni
It all begins once we rein in the threads of fate
ima atarashii yoake ga kuru
A new day will dawn for us
omoi wa kitto hitotsu
We must be one in spirit
...Harime...
Oh? Did she just overwhelm
Harime with her spirit?
（皐月）ほう 気迫で針目を
押さえつけるか
You can sit back and watch.
貴様はそこでおとなしくしていろ
Aw, I went through all that trouble
fitting Junketsu to you,
せっかく君のために仕立てた
純潔だったのに
そんなダサい格好 許せない！
but you're wearing
that lame outfit again?
I can't stand it!
Give it up.
やめておけ 私はもう
絶対に鮮血を脱がない
I'm never gonna take
Senketsu off again.
Right now, Senketsu also has Satsuki
and Mako's blood flowing through him.
今この鮮血には皐月とマコ
２人の血も流れている
純潔なんて化け物(もん)より
よっぽど暖かくて—
Compared to that monstrous
...Junketsu, he's much warmer...
着心地がいいんだよ！
and comfortable to wear!
Ryuuko!
（鮮血）流子 よく言ってくれた！
Well said!
バカ 服が泣くな！
Hey, clothing isn't supposed to bawl!
びしょびしょして
気持ち悪いだろうが
I'd feel gross if you got all soggy!
せっかくいい着心地だったのに
You're letting all that
comfort go to waste!
（鮮血）うわ〜 すまなかった
Forgive me!
Why are you two playing friends?
（縫）何？ その友達ごっこ
気持ち悪くてヘドが出る
It's so creepy I wanna hurl!
Don't you look down on us.
（流子）なめんじゃねえよ
"Friends" is too limited a word.
友達なんて言葉じゃ収まらねえ
もっと訳のわかんねえものなんだよ
The feelings I have for Mankanshoku Mako
and Senketsu aren't so easily described!
私にとっての満艦飾(まんかんしょく)マコと鮮血はな
（鮮血）え？
（マコ）私ですと？
Who, me?
Yeah, that's right. A girl who's either weak
or really damn strong, but hell if I know which,
（流子）ああそうだ 強いんだか
弱いんだかわからねえ
気が付いたら人の心の中まで
ズカズカ入り込んでくる女とか
who barges into your damn mind
before you even know it,
服のくせに泣いたり笑ったり
本気で私を心配してくれるヤツとか
and an outfit that laughs, cries,
and seriously worries about me.
そんな訳のわからない連中が
必死で私を助けてくれるんだ
These incomprehensible goofballs are
always giving everything they have to save me!
So I need to respond to their
incomprehensibility in kind!
私はその訳のわかんなさに
応えなきゃいけねえ
You lot have only
one thing on your minds:
てめえらは
たった１つのことしか見てねえ
to turn this world
into one big Life Fiber.
この世を生命戦維っていう
１枚の布にすることだけだ
でもな そんなことはさせねえ
Not on my watch, you won't.
The world's much better off being
full of these incomprehensible folk!
世の中は訳わかんねえヤツが
ウロウロしてるくらいがいいんだよ
I have no idea what you're talking about,
but you're absolutely right!
（マコ）訳わかんないけど
そのとおりだよ流子ちゃん
Keep your mouth shut
if you don't have a clue.
（縫）わかんないなら黙ってな
（マコ）ヒイ〜
Aw, jeez. This is why I hate humans.
あーもう だから人間は嫌い
Fine! Take your incomprehensibility
to Hell with you!
だったら訳のわかんないまま
死んじゃえ！
（流子）やー！
（纏）キャア！
...Dad's Sword Scissors...
（流子）父さんの断ち斬りバサミ
やっと返してもらったぞ！
are finally back where they belong!
Hmph.
フン じゃあ君が
守ろうとしている連中に—
Maybe I should have
...the guys you're trying to protect...
君を攻撃させちゃおうか
attack you instead!
Have a taste of my mental refitting!
精神仮縫い 味わうがいいわ
That's not gonna work!
無駄だ！
Too bad!
残念でした そっちはおとり
That was a decoy!
This is the end, Ryuuko!
終わりだよ 流子ちゃん
For you, maybe.
てめえがな
腕！ 腕 腕 腕 腕 腕…
My arms!
My arms! My arms! My arms! My arms! My arms!
My arms! My arms! My arms! My arms!
腕！
Do you have any idea
how much my arms are worth?!
私の腕に どれだけの
価値があると思ってるの！
このグランクチュリエの！
I'm the Grand Couturier, damn it!
（流子）だから
切り落としたんじゃねえか
That's exactly why I cut them off.
Just kidding!
な〜んてね 切り落とされても
元に戻るんだから
Cut them off all you want!
They'll be back to normal in no time!
Take that.
（流子）おら！
（縫）あー
And that.
（流子）おら！
（縫）あー！
They can prevent the
restoration of Life Fibers?
生命戦維の復活を阻止できるのか
そこまでの力が そのハサミに…
Those scissors are that powerful?
Give it up, Harime Nui!
観念しろ 針目縫
こんなことあるわけない
This can't be happening.
You seriously piss me off.
ホント ムカつくわね
どいつもこいつも！
Every last one of you!
ムカつく ムカつく ムカつく
ムカつく ムカつく…
You piss me off! You piss me off! You piss me off!
You piss me off! You piss me off! You piss me off! You piss me off!
You piss me off! You piss me off! You piss me off! You piss me off! You piss me off!
You piss me off! You piss me off! You piss me off!
You piss me off! You piss me off! You piss me off! You piss me off!
You piss me off! You piss me off! You piss me off! You piss me off! You piss me off!
Hououmaru!
（皐月）鳳凰丸(ほうおうまる)！
（犬牟田(いぬむた)）くっ…
You're not getting away!
逃がすか！ 鮮血疾風
Senketsu Gale!
Huh?
あれ？ 痛！
What?
Knock it off, Ryuuko.
（鮮血）やめておけ 流子
（流子）え？
You've lost quite a lot of blood.
（鮮血）お前も相当血を流した
深追いは危険だ
Chasing after them would be too risky.
...But these bastards are still...
（流子）しかし まだこいつらが！
鳳凰丸め
針目救出のために焦ったな
Oh, Hououmaru.
She acted far too hastily
in rescuing Harime.
（マコ）え？
（美木杉）そのとおり
Exactly.
This is what you'd call
a golden opportunity.
これはチャンスということさ
They're offering our comrades and
Life Fibers to us on a silver platter!
わざわざ向こうから—
仲間と生命戦維を
持ってきてくれたってわけだな
That's right.
（美木杉）そういうこと
さあ ぼんやりしてないで
四天王の諸君も働いた働いた
Now, stop dawdling.
Get to work, Four Devas!
Gimme those!
（蟇郡(がまごおり)）貸せ！ うお〜っ！
Seven-Plus-Two-Strong
Super Suction Saver!
九連式急急救命吸引具！
SEVEN PLUS
TWO
STRONG
SUPER
SUCTION
SAVER
ん？ お前たちは…
...You guys are...
the Tennis Club's Hakodate,
テニス部の函館(はこだて)に
TENNIS CLUB
PRESIDENT
HAKODATE OMIKO
the Boxing Club's Fukuroda,
ボクシング部の袋田(ふくろだ)
BOXING CLUB PRESIDENT
FUKURODA TAKAHARU
and so on and so forth!
YAGURUMA
KUSANOSUKE
その他
OTTE TATAMU
FUGUHARA AIZENBOU
OKURAHAMA MAIMU
FORMER ACROBATICS CLUB
Medics!
（皐月）衛生兵
（薔薇蔵(ばらぞう)）へい！
At your service!
Tend to the people we rescued!
救出された人間の手当てを
Roger that!
（薔薇蔵）がってんだ
（又郎(またろう)）がってんでい
Come on, Mankanshoku family!
（薔薇蔵）よ〜し 満艦飾一家
たまには人助けするぞ
Let's actually help people for once!
（又郎）
丸裸じゃ盗むもんないし
やる気しねえな
Not like I can steal anything
from them when they're butt naked.
（好代(すくよ)）
又郎！ いいかげんにしなさい
Cut it out, Matarou!
Aight, aight!
（又郎）やめろって やめろって
（ガッツ）ガッツ ガッツ
Guts, guts!
Sewing Club, collect all the stray Life Fibers
（伊織(いおり)）
裁縫部は生命戦維を回収
至急ラボに運べ
and get them to the lab at once!
4 hours
Remaining:
1 sec
0.5 sec
Complete
（犬牟田）回収完了
Collection complete.
Let me off!
（縫）下ろしてよ！
誰が助けてくれなんて頼んだ
I didn't ask for your help!
I haven't lost yet!
僕はまだ負けてないんだから
Calm down, Grand Couturier.
（鳳凰丸）落ち着いてください
グランクチュリエ
What can you do in that state?
そのようなお姿になられて
何ができます
Right now, you should be focusing on
completing Omnisilk Kouketsu.
今あなたが
やらなければならないのは—
神羅纐纈(しんらこうけつ)の完成のはず
それが しなくていい戦闘で
両腕を失い この失態
And yet you shamefully lost your arms
in a battle you didn't have to take part in.
羅暁(らぎょう)様にどう言い訳するのです？
How are you going to
explain this to Lady Ragyou?
Explain this? Who, me?
この僕が言い訳？ ふざけないで
You've gotta be kidding me.
Head to Honnouji Academy at once.
本能字(ほんのうじ)学園に急ぎなさい
神羅纐纈を完成させるわ
I shall complete Omnisilk Kouketsu.
Oh, and you're going to
pay for mouthing off at me.
僕にそんな大口をたたいて
あとでどうなるか覚えといて
Keep that in mind.
So long as Omnisilk Kouketsu is completed,
（鳳凰丸）
神羅纐纈さえ完成すれば
私はどうなりと
it matters not what happens to me.
（伊織）純潔はどうしましょう？
What should we do with Junketsu?
Keep it locked up for now.
（皐月）一旦 拘束しろ
（黄長瀬）消去しなくていいのか
Are you sure we
shouldn't just get rid of it?
The battle is far from over.
（皐月）まだ戦いは終わっていない
（流子）着るつもりか？ また
You're planning to put it on again?
Do you really think
you can truly wear that monster?
てめえに着こなせるのか
その化け物を
I won't make the same mistake twice.
（皐月）
同じ失敗は二度は犯さない
Big words from someone who
couldn't even synchronize with Senketsu.
（流子）鮮血と人衣一体も
できなかったお前がか
（鮮血）よせ流子
Stop it, Ryuuko.
Satsuki put her life
on the line to stop you.
皐月もお前を止めるために
命を懸けたんだ
And what of it?
（流子）だからどうした
That's not enough to write off how
high-handed she's been up until now.
今までさんざん でかい面してきた
説明にはならねえ
（皐月）私に何を求める
What do you want from me?
Let me punch you.
（流子）一発 殴らせろ
（鮮血）流子！
Ryuuko.
（流子）私が本気で殴って
それでも立っていられたら—
If you can take an all-out punch
from me and remain standing,
then I'll admit that you're
strong enough to fight by my side.
一緒に戦う力があるって
認めてやるよ
You're being unreasonable, Ryuuko!
（美木杉）流子君それはむちゃだ
人衣一体した
君の本気の攻撃を受けたら—
Any normal human would die if you attacked
them seriously in your synchronized form.
生身の人間は死ぬぞ
（流子）普通の人間じゃねえ
鬼龍院(きりゅういん)皐月様だろ？
But "Lady Kiryuuin Satsuki"
is no ordinary human, is she?
Very well. Hit me.
（皐月）わかった 殴れ
Our enemy is Kiryuuin Ragyou.
敵は鬼龍院羅暁だ
If I go down here, then I stand
no chance of winning this battle anyway.
ここで倒れるようなら
とてもこの戦い勝ち目はない
I'll show you that I can
take that fist of yours.
お前の拳 受け止めてみせよう
Prove to me that you're
not all bark and no bite.
口先だけじゃないことを見せてみな
Here I come.
いくぜ
（薔薇蔵）ぐう…
（又郎）いいい…
おりゃ〜！
Gamagoori!
（皐月）蟇郡！
（流子）てめえ邪魔すんな
Stay out of this, dammit!
What is with you guys?!
（流子）何なんだ てめえら！
You dare insult me, Matoi?
（蟇郡）俺を愚弄するのか 纏(まとい)
（流子）何？
Say what?!
Is that an "all-out punch" to you?!
それがお前の本気の拳かと
聞いている
That's right!
（流子）ああ そうだ
（蟇郡）笑止！ だったら
俺たちは なぜ生きている
Ridiculous!
Why are we still alive, then?
I thought no normal human could
survive if you attacked them seriously.
（猿投山）本気なら生身の人間は
死ぬんじゃなかったのか
（流子）てめえらが
割り込んできたからじゃねえか
It's your damn fault for butting in!
That's outrageous!
（蟇郡）言語道断！
割り込んできたから手を緩める
You held back because
someone butted in?
その程度の女に
皐月様を殴る資格はない！
A woman like you has absolutely
no right to hit Lady Satsuki!
（流子）逆切れしてんじゃねえ
Don't you snap back at me!
（猿投山）逆切れじゃねえ
マジ切れだ！
No, we're genuinely pissed off!
There's no way in hell we'd let such a
half-hearted punch hit Lady Satsuki!
そんな中途半端な拳
皐月様に触れさせてたまるか！
（皐月）お前たち 何を？
What are you guys doing?
（蛇崩）私たちの顔は皐月様の顔
私たちの手足は皐月様の手足
Our faces belong to Lady Satsuki.
Our limbs, too, belong to her.
If it's for her sake, we'll gladly be
smashed to bits or chopped to pieces!
この方のためなら砕かれても
切り落とされても悔いはない
But keep in mind that these limbs have a
mind of their own and can really take a beating.
（犬牟田）ただし この手足
勝手に動くから結構しぶといよ
We, the Four Devas of Honnouji,
（猿投山）俺たち本能字四天王は
皐月様の最強の矛にして最強の盾
are Lady Satsuki's greatest weapon
and her strongest shield!
If you wish to hit her,
you'll have to go through us first!
（蟇郡）皐月様を殴りたければ
我々を殴り倒せ
That said, it won't be easy
to bring us to our knees!
だが そう簡単にはひざまずかんぞ
What is wrong with you guys?!
（流子）何なんだよ お前ら
訳わかんねえよ
You're utterly incomprehensible!
So you have a bunch of incomprehensible
fools protecting you, just like me.
（流子）訳わかんない連中に
守られてるのは お前も同じか…
（マコ）ほお〜
（皐月）どうやらそのようだな
Sure looks like it.
In order to beat Ragyou, I have to use
...all humans as pawns to further my goals...
私は羅暁に勝つためには—
全ての人間を私のコマにして
動かさなければならない
or so I used to think.
そう思っていた
That went for you, too.
お前のこともそうだ
鮮血を着て現れたあのときから—
From the moment you
showed up dressed in Senketsu,
I tried to train you so you would
be of use against Ragyou's army.
羅暁たちに対抗するための
大きな戦力として育てようと考えた
By having you come after me,
your father's "killer",
父親の敵(かたき)と私を狙わせて
お前と鮮血の力をはかった
I tested both Senketsu's
strength and your own.
If you could stay in control of yourself
without letting your Godrobe consume you,
お前が神衣(かむい)に飲み込まれることなく
自分の意志を持っていられれば—
then you would definitely prove
useful in my coup against Ragyou.
羅暁へのクーデターのときに
必ず役に立つ
I thought I could lead you into helping the cause
against her without ever telling you the truth.
お前に真実を教えなくても
うまく誘導して
羅暁への戦力にできると
...You bitch...
てめえ
But I was sorely mistaken.
だが それは大きな間違いだった
結局 私も羅暁と同じやり方を
とっていたのだ
At the end of the day, I was
doing the same thing as Ragyou.
それでは勝てないのは当然だ
いちばん愚かだったのは私だ
Of course I couldn't defeat her that way.
...The biggest fool of all...
was me.
...Satsuki...
皐月ちゃん
But now I know that the world
is not a piece of cloth.
今わかった
世界は１枚の布ではない
何だかよくわからないものに
あふれているからこの世界は美しい
It's filled to the brim with some
pretty incomprehensible things,
and that's what makes it beautiful.
その世界を守るため
一緒に戦ってくれ 流子
Please, fight alongside me to
protect that beautiful world, Ryuuko!
（流子）フン 謝るときも
大げさだな てめえは
Man, even your apologies are overblown.
I don't even feel like
hitting you anymore.
殴る気もうせちまった
I have people I wanna protect, too,
私も守りたい連中がいる
so I agree it's high time
we stopped that mother of ours.
あの行き過ぎた母親を
止めることに異存はねえよ
Now that you've made up,
（好代）
じゃあ仲直りしたところで
ご飯にしましょう
let's eat!
（流子）
おお！ おばさんのコロッケか
Whoa! Mrs. Mankanshoku's croquettes!
そう 何だかよくわからないものを
刻んでぶち込んだコロッケよ
Yep. They're packed with all kinds
of incomprehensible things!
さあ 食べて食べて
Come now, dig in!
Yeah! If you want incomprehensible,
you've come to the right family!
（マコ）そうそう
よくわからないことに関しちゃ—
ウチがいちばんだよ
さ 皐月様も
Try some, Lady Satsuki!
...This...
（皐月）これは…
（マコ）おいしいでしょ
Isn't it great?
It really is.
（皐月）ああ おいしい
Please wash down
your meal with some tea.
（揃(そろい)）食後にはお茶もございます
（薔薇蔵･又郎･マコ）おお〜
（ガッツ）ガッツ〜
（流子）あ〜む
Ryuuko.
（鮮血）流子
（流子）ん？
（鮮血）お前 さっき
ちょっと感動しただろう
That really moved you, didn't it?
I'm talking about what Satsuki said.
（鮮血）皐月の言葉を聞いたときだ
（流子）いちいち うるせえ服だな
Man, you're one nosy outfit!
（鮮血）
素直にそう言えばいいものを
You should've just honestly said so.
Would you shut up already?
（流子）ホントうっせえよ お前
（鮮血）
かわいげのない女だよ まったく
Sheesh. There's not a
cute bone in your body.
（流子）ふ〜ん 鮮血 お前ずっと
話し相手がいなくて寂しかったな
I see how it is, Senketsu.
You've been lonely 'cos you had
no one to talk to all this time, right?
That's why you're
running your mouth now.
（流子）だから
いらんことまでしゃべってる
Of course not!
（鮮血）そんなことはない
（流子）フフフ
I don't get lonely that easily!
（鮮血）私はそんな
寂しがり屋じゃないぞ
All right, all right.
（流子）わかった わかった
Run your mouth while you still can.
無駄口はたたけるうちに
たたいておけ
すぐにそんな余裕はなくなる
Soon enough, we won't
have any time for that.
もうすぐヤツが来る
She'll be here any moment now.
It's me.
（羅暁）私だ　そうか 流子が…
Oh? Ryuuko did?
Yes. Have Nui hurry up with her work.
ああ 縫には作業を急がせろ
What troublesome girls.
やっかいな娘どもが
Did I perhaps sew the
Marionette Threads all wrong?
（羅暁）しつけ糸の縫い方を
間違えたか？
Matoi Ryuuko!
（縫）纏流子 鬼龍院皐月
絶対絶対 許さないんだから！
Kiryuuin Satsuki!
...I swear... I swear...
You're gonna pay!
What I just shot into Junketsu was
Lady Satsuki's blood, Ryuuko's blood,
（伊織）純潔に撃ち込んでいるのは
皐月様の血液と流子さんの血液
それに鮮血の生命戦維を
合わせたものです
and a dash of Senketsu's Life Fibers.
So you're trying to forcibly dye Junketsu in
Lady Satsuki's colors by using Senketsu's powers?
（美木杉）鮮血の力を使って—
純潔を無理やり
皐月様色に染め上げると
（皐月）着こなせないものを
無理に着るくらいなら—
Rather than force my arms through an outfit I can
never truly wear, it'd be better to just tailor it to my needs.
仕立て直せばいい
今さら なりふり構っては
いられない
It's too late to care about
appearances now.
The only thing on your
mind is victory, huh?
（黄長瀬）頭にあるのは
勝利だけってわけか
Looks like you've shed
everything unnecessary.
どうやら余計なものを
全部脱ぎ捨てたようだな
You're a full-fledged
Nudist in spirit, too.
あんたも立派な裸のヌーディストだ
Iori, is there anything useful here?
（皐月）伊織 こちらの戦力は？
（黄長瀬）スルーかよ
You're ignoring me?!
Rest assured. Our collection of Life Fibers
went much better than expected.
（伊織）お任せください
想像以上に生命戦維の回収に
成功しました
I will now begin producing
Ultima Uniforms.
今から極(ごく)制服の製造に
取りかかります
（美木杉）
君だけで間に合うのか？
Will you be able to do it by yourself?
I'm all the help I need.
１人で十分！
三つ星極制服 誂(あつらえ)の装
Three-Star Ultima Uniform:
THREE
STAR
ULTIMA
UNIFORM
TAILOR'S
REGALIA
Tailor's Regalia!
Kiryuuin Ragyou's ultimate objective
（皐月）鬼龍院羅暁の最終目的
is to turn every last human into Life Fibers
and cover this planet with them.
それは人類を全て生命戦維に変えて
この星を覆うことだ
It's called the "Celestial Seed
Cocoon Planet" plan.
それが天種繭星(あまつだねのまゆぼし)
CELESTIAL SEED
COCOON PLANET
Every REVOCS Inc. product
is fitted with Life Fibers.
ＲＥＶＯＣＳ(リボックス)社の製品には
全て生命戦維が織り込まれている
強力な信号を受けることで
その生命戦維は覚醒する
Those Life Fibers will awaken
once the signal is sent out,
turning the helpless masses into energy sources
and transforming all clothes into COVERS.
耐性のない人間を
エネルギー源に変えて—
全ての服はカバーズに変わる
70億のカバーズは成層圏に上がり
この星を覆い尽くす
Then seven billion COVERS will rise up into the
stratosphere and completely engulf this planet.
Is she trying to dress up the Earth?
地球に服を着せようっていうのか
ったくふざけてる
That's absurd.
人類を生命戦維に変えようとしてる
とは聞いていたが—
I'd heard that she was trying to
turn humanity into Life Fibers,
そこまで大規模な計画だったとは…
しかし何のために
but I had no idea her plan
was so massive in scale.
But for what purpose?
（皐月）生命戦維は
宇宙をさまよう生命体だ
Life Fibers are a lifeform
that wander across space.
When they reach a planet
inhabited by intelligent life,
知的生命のある星にたどりつくと
その生命体を—
they have it evolve to the point where
it's a suitable energy source for them.
自分たちのエネルギー源に
ふさわしいように進化させる
そして彼らを
戦維化して星を覆い—
After that, they turn them into
Fibers and cover up the planet,
今度はその星をエネルギー源として
爆発させ—
and then turn the planet itself into an
energy source by causing it to explode,
using that momentum to
spray new seed across space.
その勢いで新たなる種子を
宇宙にばらまく
That is how they have been able to
propagate throughout the universe.
彼らはそうやって
この宇宙で繁殖を続けているのだ
Man, that sure is one bombastic plan.
まったく
大風呂敷を広げるにも程がある
Oh, man. He did it again.
（蛇崩）あ〜あ また言っちゃった
（猿投山）あ？
どうして みんな我慢してることを
そう平気で言えるかな
How are you so nonchalant about blurting out
things that everyone else is trying not to say?
北関東のアホ猿の
デリカシーのなさには—
You Northern Kanto monkeys and your
lack of tact really drives me up the wall.
ほとほと愛想が尽きるわ
If you insult Northern Kanto one more time,
I'll turn you into konjac jelly!
それ以上 北関東をバカにすると
貴様も石灰混ぜてゆで上げるぞ
（犬牟田）やれやれ 何なのかな
このこんにゃく問答は
Good grief, are you
babbling about konjac again?
いいかげんにしろ お前たち
皐月様の御前であるぞ
Knock it off, you two!
Do not forget that you are
in the presence of Lady Satsuki!
Let them be, Gamagoori.
構うな 蟇郡
お前たちの口ゲンカを聞いていると
When I hear you guys
mouth off at each other,
やっと戻ってきたと実感できる
it makes me feel like
I'm finally back home.
Yes, ma'am!
All right.
（犬牟田）よし ＲＥＶＯＣＳ社の
通信衛星のハッキングに成功
I've managed to hack into
REVOCS' communications satellite.
原初(げんしょ)生命戦維の映像 出るよ
Here comes some live footage
of the original Life Fiber.
プロテクト固くなってて
のぞけるのはカメラだけだけど
Though, well, it's so heavily encrypted
that the only thing we can use is the camera.
Ragyou.
羅暁
The original Life Fiber is headed
toward Honnouji Academy.
（犬牟田）
原初生命戦維の目的地は
本能字学園　想定どおりだね
Our prediction was right on the money.
Honnouji Academy?
本能字学園？
That's right.
（皐月）そうだ 本能字学園に
設置された巨大発信機に—
Once the original Life Fiber is attached to the
massive transmitter installed at Honnouji Academy,
原初生命戦維を
セッティングすることで—
it'll send out the signal that will
turn all of mankind into Life Fibers.
全人類 生命戦維化の信号が
発せられる
You mean we need to destroy that
transmitter in order to put a stop to her plans?
（黄長瀬）
ヤツの計画を止めるためには—
その発信機を
ぶち壊せばいいってことか
Oh, there's just one thing
we weren't expecting.
（犬牟田）あっ！
想定外のことが１つ
（蛇崩）何？
What is it?
（犬牟田）
これ まもなく当艦に着弾
We've got incoming!
They're about to hit the ship!
Seriously, could you not report
these things at the last second?!
（蛇崩）だから そういう報告は
早くしなさいっての
Mr. Mikisugi.
（皐月）美木杉さん
（美木杉）さん付け？
"Mr."?!
ここからの作戦指揮は
あなたに任せたい
I'd like you to take charge
of our strategy from now on.
...What are you...
あ… あなた？
I will go with Ryuuko to stop Ragyou.
（皐月）
私は流子と共に羅暁を止める
前線に出る者は指揮官には向かない
Someone who battles on the frontlines
is not fit to be a commander.
I see.
（美木杉）なるほど
（皐月）四天王もわかったな
（四天王）はっ
Did you get that, Four Devas?
Yes, ma'am!
All right!
（美木杉）よし！ 僕たちは
本能字学園の発信装置の破壊
We'll focus on destroying the
transmitter at Honnouji Academy.
皐月君と流子君は鬼龍院羅暁と
原初生命戦維の足止めの—
Satsuki and Ryuuko will keep Kiryuuin Ragyou
and the original Life Fiber at bay.
This will be a two-pronged operation!
両面作戦でいく
Battle stations, everyone!
総員 配置に就け！
There you go again,
ordering people around.
また勝手に人の行動を決める
（皐月）行かないのか？
（流子）お前は行けんのか？
Aren't you going?
What about you?
（皐月）行くしかない
（流子）なら さっさと着替えろ
I have no choice but to go.
Then hurry up and change.
Lady Ryuuko,
（通信機:揃）流子様
お姉様をよろしくお願いします
please take care of your sister.
Gotcha.
わかった
L-Let's go,
（流子）いくぞ！ ね… 姉…
（皐月）フフッ
...S-S-Si...
You don't need to force yourself
to act like my sister.
無理に姉妹(きょうだい)ぶる必要はない
Your blood's flowing through
Junketsu right now.
お前の血は この純潔に流れている
それで十分だ
That's enough for me.
（流子）そうか
（皐月）ああ
That so?
Yeah.
（鮮血）お前たち
...You girls...
湿っぽいのはあとだ鮮血
じゃ いくぜ！
Save the waterworks for later.
Let's do this.
Life Fiber Synchronize:
Life Fiber Override:
（流子）人衣一体 神衣鮮血
（皐月）人衣圧倒 神衣純潔
Godrobe Senketsu!
Godrobe Junketsu!
GODROBE
SENKETSU
GOD
ROBE
JUNKETSU
（皐月）流子
（流子）ああ
Ryuuko.
Yeah.
Senketsu Gale!
鮮血疾風
SENKETSU
GALE
Grab on.
（流子）つかまれ
（皐月）手助けはいい
No need to help.
Junketsu Whirlwind!
純潔旋風
JUNKETSU
WHIRLWIND
You gained my abilities as well?
（鮮血）私の能力まで吸収したのか
（流子）やるじゃねえか
Way to go!
Let's make haste.
（皐月）急ぐぞ
（流子）ああ！
Okay.
よし！ 本能字学園に進路をとる
All right. Setting course
for Honnouji Academy!
Satsuki, the ship!
（流子）皐月 船が！
（皐月）海中にもいたのか
They were underwater too?
The hell is this?
（黄長瀬）何だこいつは
（犬牟田）
どうやら戦闘に特化した
カバーズのようだね
Looks like it's a
combat-specialized COVERS.
（猿投山）こいつ 手ごわいぞ
This one's tough!
（マコ）おりゃ〜！
本能字学園 喧嘩(けんか)部部長
満艦飾マコ ここに復活！
Honnouji Academy Fight Club President,
Mankanshoku Mako,
back in action!
FIGHT CLUB-SPEC
TWO-STAR ULTIMA UNIFORM
MANKANSHOKU MAKO
PRESIDENT
BACK IN
ACTION
Don't worry, Ryuuko.
流子ちゃん 安心して
この船は私が守る！
I'll keep this ship safe!
kurikaesu mainichi ga
My monotonous everyday life
totsuzen iro wo kaeru
Took on a new hue
sonna koto dokka nozonde itanda kedo ne
A part of me always wished for that to happen
iza to naru to
But when it actually did
okubyoumono deshita
I was too scared to act
himitsu ne
That's a secret, okay?
hitori furuete
Trembling alone
soshite kimi ni aitakute
I miss you so much
zutto mikata da yo nante ieta nara
If only I could tell you that I'll always be on your side
muteki
We could be invincible
sou sa tobitatsu toki wa futari de
When we take flight, we'll do so together
tachimukai
We'll make a stand
kakaekirenai okubyou ni
I want to keep smiling
tsuppattatte waratte itai
Even when my cowardice freezes me in place
hitori kiri zutsu ga awasatte
Every little thing will come together
ookina chikara ni naru yo
To give us great strength
ima nee kanjita
That's how I feel right now
NEXT EPISODE PREVIEW
（鮮血）
世界を１枚の布で覆う
To wrap the entire world in a single cloth. That is Ragyou's giant wrapping cloth.
A SINGLE
CLOTH
それが羅暁の大風呂敷
畳めば終わる このアニメ
GIANT WRAPPING CLOTH
This anime would also wrap up if that happened,
so Ryuuko, Satsuki, and Mako rise up to prevent it,
THIS ANIME
そうはさせじと立ち上がる
流子に皐月にマコ
TO
PREVENT IT
RYUUKO
AND
SATSUKI
MAKO
そして復活 四天王
THEN
as do the new and improved Four Devas!
次回 キルラキル
「イミテイション･ゴールド」
Next time on KILL la KILL,
"Imitation Gold"!
EPISODE 23
IMITATION GOLD